for some reason the moon is one size larger tonight
konya no tsuki wa nazeka hitomawari ookikute
it's shining brighter than it usually does
itsumo yori akaruku terasu
I trudge along the road home with my shoulders hunched
senaka wo marumete tobotobo kaeru michi
at any time I will always have a friend
donna toki mo mikata wa iru
without saying a word, it's all right to cry
nani mo iwazu naketara ii ne
once my tears dry, it will all be over
namida ga karetara owari
I need to become stronger...
motto boku ga tsuyoku naranakya
sorrow is the first step towards independence
kanashimi wa jiritsu he no ippo
how many times do I have to get hurt to forget the pain?
nando kizutsukeba itami wo wasureru
when I bleed red, I'm reminded of life
akai chi wo nagaseba inochi wo omoidasu sa
I collapse on the road with my arms and legs spread out
michi ni taore dainoji ni
I look up at the sky and think
sora wo miagete omou
true loneliness is someone without a past
shin no kodoku to wa kako no nai mono
someone who only knows the present
ima shika shiranu mono
Reanimation Jutsu: Release!
All right! We've cornered him!
（ゲンマ）よし　追い詰めた。
《意識が戻ったと思えば
このざまか…》
Just when I thought
I regained consciousness,
this happens...
何だ！？
What's that?!
《マキ：やはり手ごわい。　パクラ先生》
You're strong, after all...
Pakura Sensei.
（パクラ）マキ。
Maki...?
（マキ）パクラ先生！
Pakura Sensei?!
（デイダラ）出せっつってんだろ！
Let me out!
I've had it! I'm completely fed up!
もうキレた！
堪忍袋の緒が切れた！
I'm gonna explode, hmm!
いいかげん爆発すっぞ！　うん！
いいのか？　こら！
You okay with that, huh?
We got you sealed
with the Lightning Style,
（カンクロウ）
お前が爆発できねえように→
こっちは雷遁かましてんだ。
especially so you can't explode.
ふかしてんじゃねえよ。
いろいろと不発野郎が。
So shut your trap! You dud!
（デイダラ）芸術に不発はねえんだよ。
There are no such things
as duds in art!
Huh?!
まさか　爆発！？
No way, an explosion?!
何だ！？
What is it?!
（チヨ）これは…。
What is this?
（チョウザ）ダンさん。
Dan!
（ダン）ああ。　どうやら
誰かがうまくやったようだ。
Yeah. Looks like someone succeeded.
（ビー）ナルト！
人柱力たちが消えそうだ。
Naruto! The Jinchuriki are
gonna quit it!
Looks like Itachi did it!
どうやら　イタチが
うまく　やったようだ。
《ナルト：ありがとう　イタチ》
Thanks, Itachi!
（ビー）こっちは　まだ　うだう～だ。
But this battle ain't going anywhere!
うだうだ言ってねえで
こっちもやるってばよ。
No time to waste! Let's go!
オオノキに言え。
Tell Ohnoki...
忍連合の行く末を見届けてから→
He must secure the future of
the Allied Shinobi Forces...
俺に伝えにこい…　とな。
Only then can he come
and tell me all about it...
いったい何が？
Just what the hell is going on?
I get it...
そうか。　あのインテリ
やられやがったな…　うん。
The bookworm's been
taken down... hmm.
不発じゃん。
びっくりさせやがって。
It was a dud.
Don't scare us like that.
（デイダラ）ドッカ～ン！
うわっ！
It wasn't a dud!
不発なんかじゃねえ！
芸術は　不滅だ～！
Art is...
indestructible!
Scaring us like that...
脅かしやがって。
あっ　チヨバア。
Granny Chiyo!
いまいましい呪縛から
ようやく解放されたようだな。
Looks like I'm free
of the cursed spell.
パクラ先生！
Pakura Sensei!
Maki, do not die in vain!
マキ　つまらぬ死に方をするなよ。
先生…。
Sensei...
お前たちには　未来がある。
You all have a future...
（チヨ）どうやら
やっと死ねるようじゃな。
Looks like I can finally die...
チヨバア！
カンクロウ…。
Granny Chiyo!
Kankuro...
傀儡師の技　しかと託したぞ。
I entrust you with the techniques
of the Puppet Master.
受け継いでいきます…　チヨバア。
I accept and will take it over...
Granny Chiyo.
死んだフリも　これで終わりじゃ…。
No need to play possum anymore!
As expected, I can control
my body freely now.
思ったとおり…。
もう　意志どおりに体を動かせる。
結界を解いてくれ　チョウザ…。
Choza, please undo the barrier.
It's safe now.
もう　大丈夫だ。
It seems that way...
…のようですね。
皆　結界は　もう必要ない。
Everyone, there's no need
for the barrier.
Right!
はっ！
チョウザ…　すまなかった。
Choza, forgive me.
その印　霊化の術ですね…
わかってます。
Those signs are for the Ghost
Transformation Jutsu, aren't they?
I understand.
早く　綱手様のところへ
行ってあげてください。
Please hurry to
Lady Tsunade's side!
多くの忍を殺めてきた
この術が…。
This jutsu has killed so many shinobi...
I couldn't have imagined that
it would come in handy like this!
まさか　こんなふうに役立つとは
思いもしなかったよ…。
霊化の術！
Ghost Transformation Jutsu!
思ったとおりだ。
Just as I thought!
Souls ascending after being released
from the Reanimation Jutsu
穢土転生解放後の　昇天する魂も→
この霊化の術なら
コントロールできそうだ。
can be controlled with this jutsu too.
でも　時間は
あまり　ありそうにないですよ。
But it doesn't seem like
you have much time.
Please hurry!
急いでください。
ああ…。
Yeah...
Farewell, Choza!
Thank you for everything!
じゃあな　チョウザ…
いろいろ　ありがとう。
す　すごい…
霊体のまま　飛んでった…。
Amazing...
He flew off like a ghost!
霊化の術って　いったい…。
Just what is the Ghost
Transformation Jutsu?
It allows one to become
a living ghost
生き霊となって→
that can span long distances
to kill a foe...
距離を越えて相手にとりつき
殺す術だ…。
Originally, that is.
本来はな。
Tsunade...
《綱手…》
((里の未来のために
改革は必要なんだ。
Reform is necessary for
the future of our village.
犠牲になる者を
少しでも減らすために。
In order to keep the lives sacrificed...
to a minimum.
You're right.
（綱手）そのとおりね…。
Help me, Tsunade.
手伝ってくれるかい　綱手…。
私でよければ…。
If I can be of help to you...
I need you.
キミが必要なんだ。
ダン…。
Dan...
Let's make our dreams come true!
一緒に　夢を叶えよう！
(うん…))
Yes.
Our dreams as shinobi.
《忍の夢を…》
（青）これは…　どういうことだ？
What's going on?
Reanimation chakra is
fading steadily!
穢土転生体のチャクラが
次々に消えていくぞ！
（いのいち）各地の部隊から
報告が上がってきている。
We have reports coming in
from each battlefield.
穢土転生体が　昇天していると…。
The reanimated are turning
into souls.
Even the sealed ones,
even ones still fighting!
封印されたのも…
活動しているのもだ！
（シカク）状況から判断すれば→
The only way to explain
the situation is that...
the Reanimation has been released...
穢土転生が解除された…
ということになるが。
間違いない！
穢土転生の術が解除されたんだ！
There's no mistake.
The Reanimation Jutsu
has been released!
All right!
よし！
このことを全部隊に伝えてくれ！
Relay this news to every company!
Reporting from Headquarters.
本部より連絡。
穢土転生は解除された。
The Reanimation has been released.
繰り返す。　穢土転生　解除だ！
I repeat!
The Reanimation Jutsu
has been undone!
すごい！
みんな　消えていっている！
Amazing! They're all disappearing!
しかし…　いったい
どの部隊が　やり遂げた？
But...
Which company managed to do this?
（イタチ）俺のことを
ずっと許さなくていい。
You don't ever have to forgive me.
お前が
これから　どうなろうと…。
And no matter what you do
from here on out...
I will love you always.
俺はお前を　ずっと愛している。
（サスケ）俺は…。
I...
ユギト　やぐら。
Yugito...
Yagura...
ハン　ウタカタ。
Han...
Utakata...
Fuu...
フウ　ヒゲのじいちゃん！
Old Man Beard!
任せろってばよ！
Just leave it to us!
行っちまいやがったな。
They're gone.
Then this means
the other battles are...
《…てぇことは　他の戦場も…》
Curse Kabuto, he's failed.
《マダラ：カブトめ…　失敗したか》
Hey, what are you looking at?!
よそ見してんじゃねえよ！
You're fighting me!
お前の相手は　この俺だ！
As well as the Green Beast!
（ガイ）碧き野獣もだ！
Looks like the Reanimation
has been released.
（カカシ）穢土転生は
解除されたようだな。
それが…　どうした？
And...
what of it?
（メイ）あの光は…
いったい何なんです？
What is... that light?
The Susano'o is gone and now...
（オオノキ）スサノオが消え
更に　穢土転生の塵あくたが→
the debris from the Reanimation
is in a fierce whirlwind.
激しく舞っておる。
これは　間違いなく…。
Without a doubt, this means...
The Reanimation has been released.
穢土転生が
解放されたということだな。
What?!
（エー）何だと！？
We haven't located Kabuto yet.
カブトは　まだ捜索中のはず。
早すぎる！
It's too soon!
Even if Kabuto was found,
to be able to stop this jutsu...?
発見しただけならともかく
この術まで止めるとは…。
Who could have done this?
いったい誰が？
It doesn't matter!
誰でもよい。　誰であろうと
忍世界を守った英雄じゃ。
Whoever did it is a hero
who's saved the Shinobi World!
The heavens haven't forsaken us yet!
天は　まだ　わしらを見放しては
おらんようじゃぜ。
It appears you have able shinobi
on your side too.
（マダラ）お前のそばにも
やれる忍がいたようだな。
It can't be helped...
しかたない。
He was prepared for this?
（メイ）覚悟した？
まだじゃ！
Not yet!
He's planning a final strike
before he disappears!
消える前に１発
くらわせようという腹じゃ。
Watch out!
気をつけい！
Fire Style: Dragon Flame Caterwaul!
火遁　龍炎放歌の術！
《水遁…
いや　間に合わない！》
Water Style...
No... It won't make it in time!
（綱手）ぐっ！
Lady Hokage!
火影様！
大丈夫！
I'm all right!
《百豪の術が　切れたか！？》
The 100 Healings Jutsu has worn off!
《だが…　勝った…》
But...
we've won...
Damn!
しまった！
ん？　今のは？
What was that?!
I thought she completely
lost consciousness!
完全に
意識を失っていたはずじゃ。
《私は　もう動けなかった。
どうして？》
I couldn't move anymore...
So how?
((ダン：久しぶりだな。　俺だ　綱手。
It's been a long time... Tsunade.
ダンだ。
It's me, Dan.
Dan... How are you here?!
ダン！　なんでここに？
穢土転生が解かれたんだ。
The Reanimation has
been undone.
And I flew over here with
my Ghost Transformation Jutsu.
で　霊化の術で飛んできた。
しかし　今のは危なかったよ。
But that was a close one!
ダン…。
Dan...
変わらないね　綱手。
You haven't changed at all... Tsunade.
ダン！　私は　ずっと　あなたの…。
Dan...
I have always honored your...
時間がない。
感傷に浸っている暇はないんだ。
There's no time to wallow
in sentimentalities.
I have to go.
もう行かなくちゃいけない。
But...
そんな…。
戦って　大切な人を失うばかりが
忍の仕事じゃないよ。
Fighting and losing
precious people...
is not all there is to
being a shinobi.
I love this village and my comrades.
俺は　里も仲間たちも大好きだ。
だから守りたい。
みんなを守る存在。
So I want to protect them.
A person that protects everyone...
火影は　俺の夢だから。
Becoming the Hokage
is my dream.
ダン　私は　あなたが死んでから→
Dan!
I ran from my memories
of you for a long time,
ずっと
あなたの想いから逃げてた。
after your death.
But I've changed!
でも変わった！　そして今なら→
And now...
あなたの無念を
やりたかった想いを→
I can confirm with you
what all your regrets
もう一度　確かめられる！
and the things you wanted
to do were!
I've become the Hokage!
私は　火影になった。
でも…。
ありがとう　綱手。
But...
Thank you, Tsunade.
キミは　俺のやりたかったことを
十分　成し遂げてくれているよ。
You are fulfilling my dreams
for me just fine.
I really caused you a lot of pain.
キミには　つらい思いばかり
させてしまったね。
ごめん。
I'm sorry.
I'll be waiting for you on the other side.
向こうで待ってる。
But don't come too quickly, okay?
でも　当分は来ないでくれよ。
キミは　俺の夢　そのものだから。
For you yourself are my dream.
I was able to protect you at the end...
最後に　キミを守れたんだ。
(穢土転生されたかいも
少しはあったかな))
It appears a little bit of good did come
from being reanimated.
火影　無事か？
Hokage, are you all right?!
（マダラ）生気が戻ったな。
チャクラをもらったか？
Your vitality has returned.
And you received chakra?
ちょっと
昔の知り合いに会ってな。
I got to see an old friend
for just a little while...
すぐにまた会うことになる。
Well, you'll meet again right away.
（メイ）何？
いったい　どうなっているの？
What? What's going on anyway?
離れかけていた
マダラのチャクラが→
Madara's chakra which had begun
to separate from his body
is now clinging firmly to it.
しっかりと
体にへばりついている。
元に戻った？
Is he back to his original state?
Why? Why won't he disappear?!
なぜだ？　なぜ消えない？
穢土転生は　解除されたはずだ！
I thought the Reanimation
was undone!
Reanimation is a jutsu that
summons the dead.
穢土転生とは
死者を口寄せする術だが→
However, there is one risk...
ただひとつ　リスクがある。
Risk?
（我愛羅）リスク？
As long as one knows the signs,
（マダラ）それは
印さえ知っていれば→
the reanimated dead can
rescind the Reanimation Contract
穢土から呼ばれた死人側から→
穢土転生の口寄せ契約
そのものを→
from their end.
解除できるということだ。
契約を解除だと？
Rescind the contract?!
そうなってしまえば
これほど厄介なことはない。
When that happens,
you end up with
the biggest problem of all.
An immortal body with infinite chakra...
that can move without control.
死なぬ体　無限のチャクラ。
それが制御不能で動き出す。
まさか…。
Impossible!
術者に言っておけ。
Tell the jutsu caster...
Never use a Forbidden Jutsu carelessly.
禁術を　不用意に
使うべきではないとな。
Reanimation, release!
穢土転生　解！
What is a clan?
《一族とは　何だ？》
What is a village?
《里とは何だ？》
What is... a shinobi?
《忍とは　何だ？》
俺はいったい…。
What am I?
Found you!
（水月）み～つけた！
You guys...?
お前ら…。
（水月）よっと　こんなとこで
何やってたの？
What're you doing here?
Stopping the Reanimation.
穢土転生を止めていた。
は？
Huh?
You've always been like that.
キミ　昔からそうだよね。
You never explain things to people.
人に　ものをちゃんと
説明しようって気ないよね。
Well, it's been awhile
since we saw you,
でも　久々に会ったんだから
ちゃんと説明してもらうよ。
so you'd better tell us!
何？
What?
カブトだ。
It's Kabuto...
Huh?
カブトが　穢土転生を使っていた。
Kabuto was using the Reanimation.
How... How can that be...?
こんな…
こんなことって…。
この程度の術で縛られる
俺ではないことは→
Your ridiculously juvenile jutsu
can't hold me.
You should know that
after fighting me, right?
戦っているお前らなら
納得がいくはずだが？
Now then...
さて　スサノオ完成体→
The Perfect Susano'o...
Everyone who sees it dies...
or so they say.
あれを一度　目にした者は
死ぬといわれている。
I'm almost embarrassed
to have to do this again.
一度　引っ込めてしまった以上→
二度も出すとなると
少し　みっともない。
I already used it once...
My interest has waned,
thanks to the interference.
邪魔が入って　興がそがれた。
Perhaps I ought to go
retrieve Nine Tails instead.
そろそろ　九尾を
取りにいってもいいのだが。
What?
なんじゃと！？
Let us deal with this Madara!
((こっちのマダラは
わしらに任せい。
I swear we shall finish him off!
必ず　ケリをつける。
So relax and leave him to us!
(ここは　安心して
わしらに任せろ))
Lord Tsuchikage!
土影様　もう私たちでも→
We cannot stop him.
太刀打ちできる
相手ではありません。
We still have to fight!
それでもやるんじゃ！
ここで　こいつを止めねば！
We must stop him here!
So sad...
醜いな。
Lightning Cable!
（カカシ）雷伝！　ガイ！
おう！
Guy!
Right!
Take this! Pinky Attack!
くらえ！　小指攻撃！
はあ～っ！
Heh! You don't look too happy!
へっ　苦しそうな顔してんな。
What's that supposed to mean?
どういう意味だ？
Since you're hiding your face,
I can only guess.
顔　隠してっから　俺が勝手に
そう思って見てんだよ。
If you feel insulted,
take off that mask
悔しかったら　面とって→
and show us how composed you are!
余裕顔かましてるとこ
見せてみろってばよ！　バーカ！
Stupid!
ふん！
いいぞ　ナルト！
Nice going, Naruto!
はぁ…　相手をあおるなと
言ってきたのに。
I told him not to rile up his opponent.
Well... It seems I have
no choice but to use it.
しかたない。
やらざるをえんか。
What is that?!
あれは！
え？
A giant gourd and a bottle...
でっけえひょうたんと
壷だってばよ。
Frankly, I wanted to revive this
when the conditions were perfect.
本当なら　完全な状態で
復活させたかったのだがな。
It's only a fragment,
but it's not lacking in power.
しかし　かけらでも
その力に変わりはない。
It's taking too long.
もう　ずいぶんと遅い
約束の時間だ。
It's time!
gozen reiji akari kieta machi
At midnight, in a city where the lights are out
koyoi wa odore tipsy night
I'm going to dance tonight Tipsy Night
tsukiakari mo todokanu basho ni wa
In a place where the moonlight doesn't reach
kodoku sae mo utau machi ga aru
There's a city that brings loneliness
kuruisou na furuesou na itami dake ga
There's only a maddening pain that makes me tremble
kowaresou na nakushisou na houseki da
It's like a fragile gemstone that could be easily lost
kuraberareru koto nado ubawareru koto nado nai
There's nothing to compare it to and it can't be stolen
kimi wa kimi de ii, saa waratte misete
You should just be yourself, Now show me a smile
nani mo kangaezutomo soko ni riyuu ga nakutomo
Even you don't think, Even if there is no reason
sore koso ga subarashii hajimari
This is a wonderful beginning
saa, yoake da
Now, dawn is about to break
gozen reiji akari kieta machi
At midnight, in a city where the lights are out
furikaereba sasou black night town
I look back and it beckons me Black Night Town
We found something incredible
in one of the hideouts.
Take a look at this!
This is it! Someone
who is all-knowing.
I have to meet up with someone.
I'm leaving.
皆様　お変わりございませんか？
Huh? Who?
Orochimaru.
美空ひばりです。
What are you talking about?
You killed Orochimaru!
では最後まで
ごゆっくりお楽しみください。
Next time on Naruto Shippuden:
"Orochimaru's Return"
『木曜８時のコンサート
名曲！　にっぽんの歌』。
Don't underestimate Orochimaru.
今回は　ご覧の豪華な歌手
１０組の皆さんによる→